Guide to the Bingham Oceanographic Laboratory, Peabody Museum of Natural History, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Bingham Oceanographic Laboratory, Peabody Museum of Natural History, Yale University, records
1927-1965
RU 552
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
17.25
(42 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence and subject files documenting the operations of the Bingham Oceanographic Laboratory at Yale University. Topics include faculty and personnel, environmental issues, national biological stations and institutions, and naval reports and research.
Bingham Oceanographic Laboratory
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 33-A (YRG 33-A), Records of the Peabody Museum of Natural History.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
The Bingham Oceanographic Laboratory was formed in 1930 with the gift of the 3,000 item Bingham Oceanographic Collection by Henry Payne Bingham, Yale 1910. This rare and valuable group of oceanographic specimens, collected personally by Bingham, had been at Yale on loan since 1927. With the oceanographic collection came Albert Eide Parr, a young Norwegian who had been working at the New York Aquarium. Parr was Assistant Curator from 1927-1930, Curator of the collection from 1930-1942, and Director of the Peabody Museum from 1938-1942.
Henry Bingham was interested in more than just adding to his collection. He wanted to sponsor scientific research into the life and natural laws of the sea. Thus the laboratory was founded for pure rather than applied contractual research. Scientists were encouraged to explore any aspect of oceanography they considered significant, to pursue oceanographic knowledge for its own sake. Marine biology, biochemistry and physical oceanography were the main areas of concentration. The results of research at the lab were published in the Bulletin of the Bingham Oceanographic Collection and elsewhere. The Journal of Marine Research was founded in 1937. By 1940 the lab"s researches in pure oceanography had given it a high reputation despite its small staff.
In 1942 Parr left Bingham to become director of the American Museum of Natural History. Dr. Daniel Merriman, a biologist, was appointed to replace him. Merriman was Curator of the Bingham Oceanographic Collection from 1942-1947 and Director of the Bingham Oceanographic Laboratory from 1942-1966.
With the onset of World War II, the research emphasis at the lab switched from pure to applied and practical marine research to provide information for increased and rational use of sea materials. Following the war the work of the laboratory returned to its emphasis on pure research in planktology, taxonomy, fisheries biology, productivity, anatomy, distribution, life history, and other areas of ichthyology, and physical and chemical oceanography. In addition to publication of their research the staff of the laboratory offered courses in oceanography and ichthyology at the graduate level and were actively involved in outside activities such as popular lectures, consultation, and conferences.
Funds for the Bingham Lab were small and provided only for the care and enlargement of the collection, salary for a curator, publications, and a small fund towards construction of an oceanography building. To pay for research, the budget was supplemented by outside sources such as the Connecticut State Board of Fisheries and Game, additional funds from Harry Payne Bingham and other private benefactors, Wood"s Hole Oceanographic Institution, the National Science Foundation, the Office of Naval Research, and private corporations. The physical location of the Bingham Laboratory had been in numerous spaces within the Peabody Museum physical plant until 1959 when the Bingham Laboratory for Oceanographic and Ornithological Research was constructed behind the Peabody Museum.
In 1964 an Ad Hoc Committee of several eminent oceanographers decided other oceanographic research institutions in close proximity such as Wood"s Hole provided enough programs for students without having a center at Yale University. This decision along with decreased funding meant the end of the Bingham Oceanographic Laboratory in 1966.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence and subject files documenting the operations of the Bingham Oceanographic Laboratory at Yale University. Topics include faculty and personnel, environmental issues, national biological stations and institutions, and naval reports and research.
The records of the Bingham Oceanographic Laboratory in our holdings are not complete. The material in our possession is mainly General Correspondence, Series I, and Subject Files, Series II. Series I, General Correspondence, consists of 41 boxes of correspondence from 1927-1964 regarding preparation of the Bulletin of the Bingham Oceanographic Collection, exhibitions, receipt of fish and water samples, arrangements with boat captains and fisheries for their catches, etc. There is substantial correspondence with prominent oceanographers and ichthyologists such as Charles Marcus Breder and William Charles Schroeder. Series II, Subject Files, consists of one box of office records, personnel records, and miscellaneous from 1931-1965 and includes Peabody Museum reports, President's reports, research grant lists, staff activities, appointments and publications.
A substantial amount of material remains in the hands of the Peabody Museum, including Albert Parr correspondence 1879-[l928-1934]1938, Daniel Merriman correspondence 1965-1966, expedition data and logs, President's reports 1943-1966, films on fishing and expeditions, inventories of Bingham Oceanographic Laboratory equipment, blue-prints and construction records for the Bingham Oceanographic and Ornithological Laboratory, various ephemera (fish tags, vertebrae, water color paintings of fish, framed photographs), treasurer's statements and ledgers, academic appointment files 1959-1966, research grant applications 1960-1964 and Sears Foundation reprints.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in two series: I. General Correspondence. II. Subject Files.
Natural history; Oceanography; Science; Bingham Oceanographic Laboratory; Peabody Museum of Natural History; Yale University -- Faculty
- General Correspondence, 1927-1964; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by writer within a span of dates except where directed by the recipient to be filed elsewhere. Incoming and outgoing letters are filed together.
  - 1929-1940
    - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - B (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
    - Bearse, H. M. (Box 1, Folder 4a)
    - Bigelow, H. B. (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - Breder, C. M. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Burkenroad, M. D. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - C (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - D (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - E (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - F (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - G (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - H (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Herzog, L. K. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Higgins, E. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - I (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Intelligencer Printing Co. (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
    - Iselin, O. D. (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
    - J (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - K (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - L (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
    - M (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - N (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Nesbit, R. A. (Box 5, Folder 28-29)
    - Neville, W. C. (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - O (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - O"Malley, H. (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - P (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - R (Box 6, Folder 34-35)
    - S (Box 6, Folder 36-37)
    - Schroeder, W. C. (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Sears, Henry (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Sette, O. E. (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Smith, R. O. (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - T (Box 7, Folder 42-43)
    - U (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - U.S. Bureau of Fisheries Librarian (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - V (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - W (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - X-Y-Z (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - 1940-1942
    - A (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - B (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - C (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - D (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - E (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Eimer and Amend (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - F-G-H-I (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Intelligencer Printing Co. (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - K-L-M (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Meriden Gravure, 1941-1942 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - N-O-P-Q, 1939-1942 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - R-S (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Sears Foundation, 1939-1942 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - T-U-V-W, 1939-1942 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - Woods Hole, 1941-1942 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - X-Y-Z (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - 1942
    - A-H (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - L-Z (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - 1943
    - A-C (Box 9, Folder 67-68)
    - D-G (Box 9, Folder 69-70)
    - H (Box 9, Folder 71)
    - I-M (Box 10, Folder 72)
    - N-R, Fish Purchases (Box 10, Folder 73)
    - S-Z (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - 1944
    - A-B (Box 10, Folder 75)
    - C-D (Box 10, Folder 76)
    - E-G (Box 10, Folder 77)
    - Mussel poisoning (Box 10, Folder 78)
    - H (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - H, Hunter fish purchases (Box 11, Folder 80)
    - I-M (Box 11, Folder 81-82)
    - N-P (Box 11, Folder 83)
    - R-S (Box 11, Folder 84-85)
    - T-Z (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - 1945
    - A-D (Box 12, Folder 87)
    - E-H (Box 12, Folder 88-89)
    - I-O (Box 12, Folder 90-91)
    - P-S (Box 12, Folder 92)
    - T-Z (Box 13, Folder 93)
  - 1946
    - A-C (Box 13, Folder 94-95)
    - Bermuda Biological Station (Box 13, Folder 96)
    - D-G (Box 13, Folder 97-98)
    - H-K (Box 13, Folder 99)
    - H-K (Box 14, Folder 100)
    - L-N (Box 14, Folder 101)
    - Naval Contract - Vitamin A (Box 14, Folder 102)
    - 11th North American Wildlife Conference (Box 14, Folder 103)
    - O-R (Box 14, Folder 104)
    - Starfish (Box 14, Folder 105-106)
    - Distillation Products, Inc. (Box 15, Folder 107)
    - S-Z (Box 15, Folder 108-109)
    - Weissenberg, R. (Box 15, Folder 110)
  - 1947
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 15, Folder 111)
    - A-C (Box 15, Folder 112-113)
    - D-G (Box 15, Folder 114)
    - H-L (Box 16, Folder 115-116)
    - M-Q (Box 16, Folder 117-118)
    - New Yorker Magazine Article (Box 16, Folder 119)
    - R-S (Box 16, Folder 120)
    - T-Z (Box 16, Folder 121)
  - 1948 1948
    - A-B (Box 17, Folder 122)
    - Bermuda Biological Station, 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 123)
    - C-L (Box 17, Folder 124-125)
    - M-O (Box 17, Folder 126)
    - Meriden Gravure Co., 1945-1948 (Box 17, Folder 127)
    - Moore, E., 1945-1948 (Box 17, Folder 128)
    - P-V (Box 18, Folder 129-130)
    - Toronto Symposium (Box 18, Folder 131)
    - Upperman, W. (Box 18, Folder 132)
    - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution (Box 18, Folder 133)
    - X-Y-Z (Box 18, Folder 134)
  - 1949 1949
    - A-D (Box 18, Folder 135)
    - E-H (Box 18, Folder 136)
    - I-L (Box 18, Folder 137)
    - N-Q (Box 18, Folder 138)
    - Navy Contract (Box 19, Folder 139)
    - Peabody Museum (Box 19, Folder 140)
    - R-S-T (Box 19, Folder 141-142)
    - U-Z (Box 19, Folder 143)
  - 1950
    - A (Box 19, Folder 144)
    - B (Box 19, Folder 145-146)
    - C-D (Box 19, Folder 147)
    - E-H (Box 20, Folder 148-149)
    - I-N (Box 20, Folder 150)
    - O-S (Box 20, Folder 151-152)
    - T-V (Box 20, Folder 153-154)
    - Y-Z (Box 20, Folder 155)
    - Yale-New Zealand Expedition (Box 20, Folder 156)
  - 1951
    - A (Box 21, Folder 157)
    - B (Box 21, Folder 158)
    - C (Box 21, Folder 159)
    - D-F (Box 21, Folder 160)
    - Globes (Box 21, Folder 161)
    - G (Box 21, Folder 162)
    - H (Box 21, Folder 163)
    - I (Box 21, Folder 164)
    - J (Box 21, Folder 165)
    - K (Box 21, Folder 166)
    - L (Box 21, Folder 167)
    - Mc (Box 21, Folder 168)
    - M (Box 21, Folder 169)
    - N (Box 21, Folder 170)
    - O (Box 21, Folder 171)
    - P (Box 21, Folder 172)
    - R (Box 21, Folder 173)
    - S (Box 21, Folder 174)
    - T (Box 21, Folder 175)
    - U (Box 22, Folder 176)
    - V (Box 22, Folder 177)
    - W (Box 22, Folder 178)
    - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution (Box 22, Folder 179-180)
    - Y (Box 22, Folder 181)
    - Z (Box 22, Folder 182)
  - 1952
    - A (Box 22, Folder 183)
    - American Institute of Biological Science (Box 22, Folder 184)
    - Austin, T. S. (Box 22, Folder 185)
    - B (Box 22, Folder 186)
    - Bermuda Biological Station (Box 22, Folder 187)
    - C (Box 22, Folder 188)
    - Chamber of Commerce (Box 22, Folder 189)
    - D (Box 22, Folder 190)
    - E (Box 22, Folder 191)
    - F (Box 22, Folder 192)
    - G (Box 22, Folder 193)
    - H (Box 23, Folder 194)
    - I (Box 23, Folder 195)
    - Intelligencer Printing Co. (Box 23, Folder 196-196a)
    - I.C.N.A.F. (Box 23, Folder 197)
    - J (Box 23, Folder 198)
    - K (Box 23, Folder 199)
    - Kestevan Report, etc. (Box 23, Folder 200)
    - L (Box 23, Folder 201)
    - Mc (Box 23, Folder 202)
    - M (Box 23, Folder 203)
    - N (Box 23, Folder 204)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 23, Folder 205)
    - Navy (Box 23, Folder 206)
    - Navy - Reviews of Oceanography (Box 23, Folder 207)
    - Navy - Riley Reports (Box 23, Folder 208)
    - Navy - Riley (Box 23, Folder 209)
    - O (Box 23, Folder 210)
    - P (Box 23, Folder 211)
    - Peabody Museum (Box 23, Folder 212)
    - R (Box 23, Folder 213)
    - S (Box 24, Folder 214)
    - T (Box 24, Folder 215)
    - Thompson., Capt. E. (Box 24, Folder 216)
    - U (Box 24, Folder 217)
    - V (Box 24, Folder 218)
    - W (Box 24, Folder 219)
    - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution (Box 24, Folder 220)
    - Y (Box 24, Folder 221)
    - Z (Box 24, Folder 222)
  - 1953
    - A (Box 24, Folder 223)
    - American Institution of Biological Sciences (Box 24, Folder 224)
    - B (Box 24, Folder 225)
    - Bermuda Biological Station (Box 24, Folder 226)
    - C (Box 24, Folder 227)
    - D (Box 24, Folder 228)
    - E (Box 24, Folder 228a)
    - F (Box 24, Folder 229)
    - G (Box 24, Folder 230)
    - H (Box 24, Folder 231)
    - I (Box 24, Folder 232)
    - Intelligencer Printing Co. (Box 24, Folder 233)
    - Intelligencer Printing Co. (Box 25, Folder 234)
    - I.C.N.A.F. (Box 25, Folder 235-236)
    - K (Box 25, Folder 237)
    - Kestevan (Box 25, Folder 238)
    - L (Box 25, Folder 239)
    - Mc (Box 25, Folder 240)
    - M (Box 25, Folder 241)
    - Migdalski, re: 51 Hillhouse, 1952-1953 (Box 25, Folder 242)
    - N (Box 25, Folder 243)
    - Navy - Riley (Box 25, Folder 244)
    - Navy (Box 25, Folder 245)
    - Navy - Riley Reports (Box 25, Folder 246)
    - O (Box 25, Folder 247)
    - P (Box 25, Folder 248)
    - Q (Box 25, Folder 249)
    - R (Box 25, Folder 250)
    - Science II B (Box 25, Folder 251)
    - Striped Bass (Box 25, Folder 252)
    - S (Box 25, Folder 253)
    - T (Box 26, Folder 254)
    - Thompson, Capt. E. (Box 26, Folder 255)
    - U (Box 26, Folder 256)
    - V (Box 26, Folder 257)
    - W (Box 26, Folder 258)
    - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution (Box 26, Folder 259)
    - Y (Box 26, Folder 260)
    - Z (Box 26, Folder 261)
  - 1954
    - A (Box 26, Folder 262)
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences (Box 26, Folder 263)
    - B (Box 26, Folder 264)
    - Bermuda Biological Station (Box 26, Folder 265)
    - C (Box 26, Folder 266)
    - D (Box 26, Folder 267)
    - E (Box 26, Folder 268)
    - F (Box 26, Folder 269)
    - Farrington - Fishing the Pacific (Box 26, Folder 270)
    - G (Box 26, Folder 271)
    - H (Box 26, Folder 272)
    - I (Box 26, Folder 273)
    - Intelligencer Printing Co. (Box 26, Folder 274)
    - J (Box 26, Folder 275)
    - K (Box 26, Folder 276)
    - L (Box 27, Folder 277)
    - Mc (Box 27, Folder 278)
    - Migdalski - 51 Hillhouse (Box 27, Folder 279)
    - M (Box 27, Folder 280)
    - N (Box 27, Folder 281)
    - Navy - Riley (Box 27, Folder 282)
    - Navy (Box 27, Folder 283)
    - O (Box 27, Folder 284)
    - P (Box 27, Folder 285)
    - Q (Box 27, Folder 286)
    - R (Box 27, Folder 287)
    - S (Box 27, Folder 288)
    - Science IIB (Box 27, Folder 289)
    - State Board of Fisheries and Game, Hartford (Box 27, Folder 290)
    - T (Box 27, Folder 291)
    - V (Box 27, Folder 292)
    - W (Box 27, Folder 293)
    - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution (Box 27, Folder 294)
    - X-Y (Box 27, Folder 295)
    - Z (Box 27, Folder 296)
  - 1955
    - Atlantic States Fisheries Commission (Box 27, Folder 297)
    - A (Box 27, Folder 298)
    - B (Box 27, Folder 299)
    - Bermuda Biological Station (Box 27, Folder 300)
    - C (Box 27, Folder 301)
    - D (Box 27, Folder 302)
    - E (Box 28, Folder 303)
    - F (Box 28, Folder 304)
    - G (Box 28, Folder 305)
    - H (Box 28, Folder 306)
    - I (Box 28, Folder 307)
    - J (Box 28, Folder 308)
    - K (Box 28, Folder 309)
    - L (Box 28, Folder 310)
    - Mc (Box 28, Folder 311)
    - M (Box 28, Folder 312)
    - N (Box 28, Folder 313)
    - Navy - Riley (Box 28, Folder 314)
    - O (Box 28, Folder 315)
    - P (Box 28, Folder 316)
    - R (Box 28, Folder 317)
    - S (Box 28, Folder 318)
    - Science IIB (Box 28, Folder 319)
    - State Board of Fisheries and Game, Hartford (Box 28, Folder 320)
    - T (Box 28, Folder 321)
    - Tuna Match (Box 28, Folder 322)
    - V (Box 28, Folder 323)
    - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution (Box 28, Folder 324)
    - W (Box 28, Folder 325)
    - X-Y (Box 28, Folder 326)
    - Z (Box 28, Folder 327)
  - 1956
    - A (Box 29, Folder 328)
    - B (Box 29, Folder 329)
    - Bermuda Biological Station (Box 29, Folder 330)
    - C (Box 29, Folder 331)
    - D (Box 29, Folder 332)
    - E (Box 29, Folder 333)
    - F (Box 29, Folder 334)
    - G (Box 29, Folder 335)
    - Hawley School, Newton, Conn. - Reports (Box 29, Folder 336)
    - H (Box 29, Folder 337)
    - Intelligencer Printing Co. (Box 29, Folder 338)
    - I (Box 29, Folder 339)
    - J (Box 29, Folder 340)
    - K (Box 29, Folder 341)
    - L (Box 29, Folder 342)
    - Mc (Box 29, Folder 343)
    - M (Box 29, Folder 344)
    - Migdalski - 51 Hillhouse (Box 29, Folder 345)
    - Navy - Riley (Box 29, Folder 346)
    - N (Box 29, Folder 347)
    - O (Box 29, Folder 348)
    - Pickford (Box 29, Folder 349)
    - P (Box 29, Folder 350)
    - R (Box 29, Folder 351)
    - S (Box 29, Folder 352)
    - Science IIB (Box 30, Folder 353)
    - Seychelles Expedition (Box 30, Folder 354)
    - T (Box 30, Folder 355)
    - V (Box 30, Folder 356)
    - W (Box 30, Folder 357)
    - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution (Box 30, Folder 358-359)
    - Z (Box 30, Folder 360)
  - 1957
    - A (Box 30, Folder 361)
    - B (Box 30, Folder 362)
    - Bermuda Biological Station (Box 30, Folder 363)
    - C (Box 30, Folder 364)
    - D (Box 30, Folder 365)
    - E (Box 30, Folder 366)
    - F (Box 30, Folder 367)
    - G (Box 30, Folder 368)
    - H (Box 30, Folder 369)
    - J (Box 30, Folder 370)
    - K (Box 30, Folder 371)
    - L (Box 30, Folder 372)
    - M (Box 30, Folder 373)
    - Migdalski - 51 Hillhouse (Box 30, Folder 374)
    - N (Box 30, Folder 375)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 30, Folder 376)
    - Navy (Box 30, Folder 377)
    - Navy-Riley (Box 30, Folder 378)
    - O (Box 30, Folder 379)
    - Pickford (Box 30, Folder 380)
    - P (Box 30, Folder 381)
    - R (Box 30, Folder 382)
    - S (Box 31, Folder 383)
    - T (Box 31, Folder 384)
    - U (Box 31, Folder 385)
    - V (Box 31, Folder 386)
    - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution (Box 31, Folder 387)
    - W (Box 31, Folder 388)
    - Z (Box 31, Folder 389)
  - 1958
    - A (Box 31, Folder 390)
    - Applicants for Jobs (Box 31, Folder 391)
    - Bermuda Biological Station (Box 31, Folder 392)
    - B (Box 31, Folder 393-394)
    - C (Box 31, Folder 395)
    - D (Box 31, Folder 396)
    - Editorial - Journal Bulletin (Box 31, Folder 397)
    - E (Box 31, Folder 398)
    - F (Box 31, Folder 399)
    - G (Box 31, Folder 400)
    - H (Box 31, Folder 401)
    - Intelligencer Printing Co. (Box 31, Folder 402)
    - I (Box 31, Folder 403)
    - J (Box 31, Folder 404)
    - K (Box 31, Folder 405)
    - L (Box 31, Folder 406)
    - M (Box 31, Folder 407)
    - Migdalski (Box 31, Folder 408)
    - Mc (Box 31, Folder 409)
    - N (Box 31, Folder 410)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 31, Folder 411)
    - Navy - Riley (Box 31, Folder 412)
    - O (Box 31, Folder 413)
    - Pickford (Box 31, Folder 414)
    - P (Box 31, Folder 415)
    - R (Box 31, Folder 416)
    - S (Box 32, Folder 417)
    - State Board of Fisheries and Game - Hartford (Box 32, Folder 418)
    - T (Box 32, Folder 419)
    - U (Box 32, Folder 420)
    - V (Box 32, Folder 421)
    - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution (Box 32, Folder 422)
    - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution - Committee on new Director (Box 32, Folder 423)
    - W (Box 32, Folder 424)
    - Z (Box 32, Folder 425)
  - 1959
    - American Institute of Biological Science (Box 32, Folder 426)
    - American Society of Zoologists (Box 32, Folder 427)
    - Applications - student (Box 32, Folder 428)
    - A (Box 32, Folder 429)
    - Bermuda Biological Station (Box 32, Folder 430)
    - Bulletin: Bingham Oceanographic Collection (Box 32, Folder 431)
    - B (Box 32, Folder 432)
    - Cape Haze Marine Laboratory (Box 32, Folder 433)
    - Coastal Studies Project (Box 32, Folder 434)
    - C (Box 32, Folder 435)
    - D (Box 32, Folder 436)
    - E (Box 32, Folder 437)
    - F (Box 32, Folder 438)
    - G (Box 32, Folder 439)
    - H (Box 32, Folder 440)
    - International Oceanographic Congress (Box 32, Folder 441)
    - I (Box 32, Folder 442)
    - J (Box 32, Folder 443)
    - K (Box 32, Folder 444)
    - Kristiakowsky (Box 33, Folder 445)
    - L (Box 33, Folder 446)
    - M (Box 33, Folder 447)
    - Marine Research Laboratory (Box 33, Folder 448)
    - Meteorological Institute (Box 33, Folder 449)
    - Migdalski (Box 33, Folder 450)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 33, Folder 451)
    - N.A.S. Committee on Oceanographic Research (Box 33, Folder 452)
    - N.S.F. Proposals (Box 33, Folder 453)
    - Navy (Box 33, Folder 454)
    - New York Zoological Society (Box 33, Folder 455)
    - O (Box 33, Folder 456)
    - Pickford (Box 33, Folder 457)
    - P (Box 33, Folder 458)
    - R (Box 33, Folder 459)
    - Recommendations (Box 33, Folder 460)
    - S (Box 33, Folder 461)
    - T (Box 33, Folder 462)
    - U (Box 33, Folder 463)
    - V (Box 33, Folder 464)
    - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution (Box 33, Folder 465-466)
    - W (Box 33, Folder 467)
    - X-Y-Z (Box 33, Folder 468)
  - 1960
    - Applications - student (Box 33, Folder 469)
    - A (Box 33, Folder 470)
    - Bermuda Biological Laboratory (Box 33, Folder 471)
    - Bingham Laboratory Advisory Committee (Box 33, Folder 472)
    - B (Box 34, Folder 473)
    - Cooper Fund (Box 34, Folder 474)
    - C (Box 34, Folder 475)
    - E (Box 34, Folder 476)
    - F (Box 34, Folder 477)
    - G (Box 34, Folder 478)
    - H (Box 34, Folder 479)
    - Inter-American Tuna Commission (Box 34, Folder 480)
    - International Council for Exploration of the Sea (Box 34, Folder 481)
    - Kistiakowski Committee (Box 34, Folder 482)
    - K (Box 34, Folder 483)
    - L (Box 34, Folder 484)
    - M (Box 34, Folder 485)
    - NAS - NRC - Aquatic Biology Committee (Box 34, Folder 486)
    - NAS - NRC - Committee on Oceanography (Box 34, Folder 487-488)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 34, Folder 489)
    - N (Box 34, Folder 490)
    - O (Box 34, Folder 491)
    - Peabody Museum Advisory Committee (Box 34, Folder 492)
    - President"s Scientific Advisory Committee (Box 34, Folder 493)
    - P (Box 34, Folder 494)
    - R (Box 34, Folder 495)
    - Recommendations (Box 34, Folder 496)
    - Requests for Information (Box 34, Folder 497)
    - S (Box 34, Folder 498)
    - Sea Frontiers article (Box 34, Folder 499)
    - Ships and Salvage (Box 35, Folder 500)
    - TV (Box 35, Folder 501)
    - T (Box 35, Folder 502)
    - U.S. Navy Hydrographic Office (Box 35, Folder 503)